Based in: London, NW10 7GL, UK

Marius OLARIU

marius.lucian.olariu @gmail.com linkedin.com/in/mlo1994

Summary

I am a degree educated Software Engineer with more than 4 years of experience in developing Web and desktop apps. I developed software for various industries like supply chain, project management, unit test creation using Reinforcement Learning and now pharma industry. The best professional quality that I have is the love for learning and my ideal role is one where this is encouraged and supported. I love technology, growth and productivity. Given this, I have a strong preference to work on a MacBook Pro. In my professional career, I worked with technologies like Java, JavaScript, Groovy, SQL, Spring, Grails, AWS, React and others. I have EU pre-settled status and I have the right to work in the UK.

Employment

Full-stack Sofware Engineer

IQVIA

Feb 2022 - present

Full-stack development for an eSource system designed to support the drug development process; the software is used by the biggest pharma companies in the world (e.g 3 of top 5 pharma companies). We heavily rely on AWS to scale up and down and thus some of my tasks involve looking at the infrastructure and trying to troubleshoot certain problems our customers encounter in production. Apart from this I like to help people onboard with product development so at the moment I am helping a new developer to get started.

Technologies used: Groovy, Grails, Java, AWS, JavaScript, SQL, Git, HTML, CSS

Product developed: https://www.clinspark.com/

Sofware Engineer

Diffblue

Aug 2020 - Feb 2022 (1y 7m)

In this role, I am writing software in Java in an Agile environment for Diffblue Cover, a tool powered by AI that automatically generates (unit) tests for Java code. I make a consistent commitment to growth by embracing continuous learning (i.e. each Sprint I study a topic relevant for my work) and by taking new responsibilities (e.g. lead stand-ups and Sprint Retrospectives). Last, but not least, I set up and maintained an online environment where the product could be tried.

Technologies used: Java, Spring (a bit), JUnit, Maven, Git **Product developed**: https://www.diffblue.com/products/

Junior Full-stack Engineer

New Verve Consulting

Aug 2019 - Aug 2020 (1y)

Played an important role in the development and launch of a cloud add-on for Jira. The add-on allows you to bring context to Jira tickets by linking them to customer data. I helped through pair-programming sessions one of my colleagues to transition from a Technical Consultant position to a Developer one. Managed my time between writing my MSc dissertation and the position successfully.

Technologies used: JavaScript, React, Node, Jest, Git, HTML, CSS

Product developed: https://bit.ly/3zKtngM

Junior Software Engineer

SSI Schaefer Romania

Sept. 2017 - Aug 2018 (1y)

Got exposed to the world of professional software development with Java as well as finished my last year of BSc studies in Computer Science. I worked on the development of software for a vertical lift module (LOGIMAT) that allowed goods in a warehouse to be stored and managed efficiently. Managed my time successfully between the position and my last year of BSc studies.

Technologies used: Java, SQL, JUnit, HQL, Git

Product developed: https://logimat.ssi-schaefer.com/logimat-en-gb

Education

Paisley, Scotland

West University Scotland

Sept 2018 - Feb 2020

- Received an MSc degree with distinction in "Mobile Web Development"
- MSc thesis: Development and Evaluation of the User Experience of a Mobile Booking Application
- Courses: Web Development, Mobile Networks and Smartphone Apps, Human-Computer Interaction etc.

Timisoara, Romania

Polytechnic University

Sept 2014 - June 2018

- Received a Bachelor degree with distinction in "Computer and Software Engineering"
- BSc project: HelpMeSee Navigation assistant for visually impaired people
- Courses: Computer Programming, Algorithms, Operating Systems, Databases etc.

Nijmegen, The Netherlands

Radboud University

Feb 2017 - Jul 2017

• exchange semester through Erasmus programme

Linköping, Sweden

Linköping University

Sept 2016 - Jan 2017

• exchange semester through Erasmus programme

Technical Experience

Personal Projects

- Plus One Mentor App (2019) Mobile and Web solution for the youth work of YMCA Paisley and also used
 for my MSc research. This mobile solution allows YMCA volunteers to schedule appointments with mentees
 and also to provide feedback on them. The Web solution allows the manager to see an activity overview for
 each YMCA volunteer within his organization. Java API Android, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Firebase Solutions,
 Git
- **HelpMeSee** (2018) Navigation assistant for visually impaired people, namely an Android application through which the visually impaired user can set a certain destination and will receive real-time voice instruction on how to get to it. Demo video, code and documentation can be found on my GitHub account. Java API Android, MVC architecture, LaTeX documentation, *git*
- WordWar (2017) Android multiplayer game for language learning. The game looks similar to a Trivia game, namely, the players compete to conquer tiles of the map by remembering the word translation. Java LibGDX
- RoboApp (2016) Android app working as a remote control for a robo-car. The app was developed during a student competition organized by Continental Automotive Romania, "inGENIUOSLY". The aim of the competition was to build an "autonomous" robo-car that had to get out of a maze city by detecting traffic signs as fast as possible. Java API Android

Additional Experience and Awards

- SFC Scholarship (2018). A scholarship awarded by the Scottish Funding Council (SFC) that covered the tuition fee for my master degree programme.
- Third Prize, inGENIOUSly (2016). My team received this prize at the "inGENIOUSly" competition organized by Continental Automotive Romania.

Volunteering

Paisley, Scotland

YMCA Paisley

Sept 2018 - Aug 2019

- I went to a coding club for young people (7 18 years old) where I helped them learn programming through gamification.
- More info can be found at http://www.paisleyymca.org/

Online

- GitHub: https://github.com/mariusolariu
- Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mlo1994

Soft Skills

- I consider myself: optimistic, self-motivated, team-player and friendly.
- languages: Romanian (native), English (fluent)
- driving licence (2012)